Homer Leroy Shantz papers, 1903-1958
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Homer Leroy Shantz papers, 1903-1958
MS 030
Shantz, H.L. (Homer LeRoy), 1876-1958
Field notebooks, reprint articles, speeches, survey abstracts, photographs, diaries, and correspondence pertaining to Shantz's interests in worldwide agriculture and botany. Shantz's various trips to Africa resulted in extensive field notes, including those for the Smithsonian African Expedition, 1919 to 1920, and the African Education Commission, 1923 to 1924. Background material he collected about Africa encompasses maps; postcards; dictionaries and primers on languages, including Swahili; also, articles on the people, the areas they inhabited, and specific problems, such as the tsetse fly, sleeping sickness, forced labor, and race relations. Photographs of his travels from the Cape to Cairo depict the Nile, Egyptian ruins, wild and domestic animals, vegetation and the landscape, villages and cities, and people in tribal dress. Communal activities documented include cultivation, thatching roofs, building a road, and weaving a large bamboo mat to cover a bridge walkway.
13.6 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Plant physiologist for the U.S. Dept. of Agriculture; Botany professor at several universities; later, Chief of Wildlife Management Division, U.S. Forest Service.
Scope and Content Note
Field notebooks, reprint articles, speeches, survey abstracts, photographs, diaries, and correspondence pertaining to Shantz's interests in worldwide agriculture and botany. Shantz's various trips to Africa resulted in extensive field notes, including those for the Smithsonian African Expedition, 1919 to 1920, and the African Education Commission, 1923 to 1924. Background material he collected about Africa encompasses maps; postcards; dictionaries and primers on languages, including Swahili; also, articles on the people, the areas they inhabited, and specific problems, such as the tsetse fly, sleeping sickness, forced labor, and race relations. Photographs of his travels from the Cape to Cairo depict the Nile, Egyptian ruins, wild and domestic animals, vegetation and the landscape, villages and cities, and people in tribal dress. Communal activities documented include cultivation, thatching roofs, building a road, and weaving a large bamboo mat to cover a bridge walkway.
United States material primarily concerns the West, with a focus on Colorado. A study of its vegetation changes includes over 200 photographs. Items from other countries are South American survey abstracts by various authors; Shantz's diary and notes from the International Phytogeographic Expedition to Switzerland, 1923; also his field notes and diaries from Ontario, 1916; the U.S.S.R., 1930; and Germany, 1934. Correspondence concerns his various projects. The bound reprints of his writings have some material concerning wildlife, as it relates to larger ecological schemes.
Access Terms
Shantz, H.L. (Homer LeRoy), 1876-1958 -- Archives
Smithsonian African Expedition, 1919-1920
Plant ecology -- Africa
Plant ecology -- United States
Vegetation surveys -- South America
Vegetation surveys -- Colorado
Vegetation surveys -- Africa
Swahili language -- Dictionaries -- English
English language -- Dictionaries -- Swahili
Agriculture -- Africa
Soils -- Africa
Agriculture -- United States
Soils -- United States
Africa -- Description and travel
Africa -- Description and travel
Africa -- Social life and customs
Correspondence
Diaries
Photographs
Field Notes
Reprints
Related Material
All slides and negatives mentioned in the Shantz notebooks and papers are on the file in the University of Arizona Herbarium.
Container List
- Travel Notes. 1911-1913 (Box 1)
  Typescripts, with photographs, on the natural vegetation of western U.S. Compiled while serving as Plant Physiologist, U.S. Department of Agriculture.
- Travel Notes. 1916 (Box 2)
- Travel Notes. 1917 (Box 3)
- Travel Notes. 1918, 1922 (Box 4)
- African Trip, (p.1-392). 1919 (Box 5)
  Typescript, with photographs: Travel Notes on a Trip Through Africa from Cape to Cairo. Smithsonian African Expedition.
- African Trip, (p.393-666). 1919 (Box 6)
- African Trip, (6 holograph notebooks). 1919 (Box 7)
- African Trip: Itinerary. 1919 (8, Folder 1)
- African Trip: Collections and Trophies. 1919 (Box 8, 2)
- African Trip: Expense Accounts. 1919 (Box 8, 3)
- African Trip: Movies. 1919 (Box 8, 4)
- African Trip: Sorghum Material. 1919 (Box 8, 5)
- African Trip: Miscellaneous Material. 1919 (Box 8, 6)
- African Trip: Postcards. 1919 (Box 8)
- African Trip: Author's work copy of published report: The Vegetation and Soils of Africa. 1923 (Box 8)
- African Survey Abstracts. (Box 9)
  Abstracts of articles by various authors on South African vegetation.
- African Survey Abstracts. (Box 10)
- Africa: Background Material on Areas. (Box 11, 1-2)
- Africa: Dictionaries and primers. (Box 11, 3)
- Africa: Maps. (Box 11, 4)
- Africa: Rainfall. 1957 (Box 11, 5)
- Africa: Slavery and Forced Labor. 1925-1926 (Box 11, 6)
- Africa: Vegetation Photographs (from previously published sources). (Box 11, 7)
- Africa: Photographs (various trips). (Box 11, 8)
- Africa: Tsetse Fly. (Box 11, 9)
- Africa: Reviews. (Box 11, 10)
- Africa: African Movies. 1924 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Africa: African Notes. 1924, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Africa: Articles by H.S.L. (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Africa: African Collections (seeds, grasses, soils). 1921, 1924 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Africa: "Abyssinia." Chamber Lecture. (Includes article about the Ethiopian map given to H.L.S. by Haile Selassie). April 1935 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Africa: Atlantic Charter and Africa. (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Africa: Race Problems; New Africa (periodical). 1943-1947 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Africa: Wilderness Idea. 1950, 1957-1958 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Africa: Jungle Man, the autobiography of Major P.J. Pretorius, Dutton. H.L.S.'s personal copy with photos tipped in. 1948 (Box 12)
- Colorado Survey: Changes in Vegetation and Land Use in Eastern Colorado, 1904-1949 by H.L. Shantz and Ned A. Smith. Rocky Mountain Forest & Range Experiment Station, Fort Collins, Colo. Mimeographed with holograph corrections. "Corrected work copy to be used for final copy. H.L.S." 1953 (13, Folder 1)
- Colorado Survey: Changes in Natural Vegetation and Land Use in the Plains and Along the Eastern Mountain Front in Colorado by H.L.Shantz and W.G. McGinnies. Original typescript with holograph corrections. 2nd draft. (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Colorado Survey: Mounted Photographs, #80-203, A-Z, AA-EE. (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Colorado Survey. Mounted Photographs, #80-203, A-Z, AA-EE. (Box 14)
- South American Survey Abstracts. (Box 15)
  Abstracts of articles by various authors on South American vegetation.
- South American Survey Abstracts. (Box 16)
- Personal Papers: Bibliography of H.L.S. (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Personal Papers: Miscellaneous Personal Material. (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Personal Papers: Regarding H.L.S.'s address at President Richard A. Harvill's Inauguration, University of Arizona. November 1951 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Personal Papers: Articles Not in Bound Volumes. Natural Vegetation and What It Indicates. 1908-1909 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Personal Papers: Articles Not in Bound Volumes. Water as a Factor in Plant Growth. 1916 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Personal Papers: Articles Not in Bound Volumes. Sagebrush Stem with R.L. Piemeisel. 1929-1953 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Personal Papers: Articles Not in Bound Volumes. (Various). 1930-1956 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Personal Papers: Articles Not in Bound Volumes. (Undated and Fragments.) (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Personal Papers: Diaries. 1904, 1907, 1919 (Box 17)
- Personal Papers: Notebook, containing diary and notes made during the International Phytogeographic Expedition to Switzerland in 1923, Pledge to Nature, notes on reading, and an itinerary of his world travels. 1891-1943 (Box 17)
- Correspondence: Miscellaneous. 1900, 1917-1927, 1936-1958 (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
- Correspondence: Breazeale, J.F. (USDA, Bureau of Plant Industry). 1919-1925 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Correspondence: Nelson, DeWitt (California State Forester). 1946-1947 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Correspondence: Grassland Research Foundation, Inc. 1939-1956 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Correspondence: Climatic Conditions in Colorado. 1950-1953 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Correspondence: Navajo Research Project. 1951-1952 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Correspondence: Regarding an Unpublished Manuscript by Peter Riedel. 1955-1958 (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Project on Vegetation Change in East and South Africa. (Sponsored by the Office of Naval Research) Correspondence and miscellaneous material. 1955-1958 (Box 18, Folder 10-12)
- Project on Vegetation Change in East and South Africa. (Sponsored by the Office of Naval Research) Miscellaneous material. (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Project on Vegetation Change in East and South Africa. (Sponsored by the Office of Naval Research) Correspondence and miscellaneous material. 1955-1958 (Folder 13)
- Reprints, I. 1905-1953 (Volume 19)
  These bound volumes were arranged and bound by Dr. Shantz. They contain both printed and typescript copies of articles and speeches by him, 1905-1953.
- Reprints, II. 1905-1953 (Volume 20)
- Reprints, III. 1905-1953 (Volume 21)
- Reprints, IV. 1905-1953 (Volume 22)
- Reprints, V. 1905-1953 (Volume 23)
- Reprints, VI. 1905-1953 (Volume 24)
- Reprints, VII. 1905-1953 (Volume 25)
- Reprints, VIII. 1905-1953 (Volume 26)
- Pot Experiments. June-July 19--? (Box 27, Folder 1)
- Plants Turned in to National Herbarium. 1903-1904 (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Summary of Negatives. 1907 (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Experiments (Louisiana; Missouri). 1907-1908 (Box 27, Folder 4)
- Field Notes (Louisiana; Missouri). 1907-1908 (Box 27, Folder 5)
- Notes on Vegetation. 1908 (Box 27, Folder 6)
- Summary (Photos; Soils). 1908 (Box 27, Folder 7)
- Soils I (Colorado). 1907-1910 (Box 27, Folder 8)
- Soils II (Colorado; Nebraska; Arizona; Nevada). 1909-1910 (Box 27, Folder 9)
- Soils III (Arizona). 1911 (Box 27, Folder 10)
- Photos. 1909 (Box 27, Folder 11)
- Work. 1909 (Box 27, Folder 12)
- Work. 1901 (Box 27, Folder 13)
- Indicator Plants. 1900-1911 (Box 27, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous Notes. 1910-1911 (Box 27, Folder 15)
- Photos. 1910 (Box 27, Folder 16)
- Field Notes. (Texas; Colorado). April-June 1910 (Box 27, Folder 17)
- Field Notes (Colorado). June 1910 (Box 27, Folder 18)
- Field Notes (Colorado). July 1910 (Box 27, Folder 19)
- Field Notes (Utah; Nevada; California; Oregon). July-August 1910 (Box 27, Folder 20)
- Field Notes (Pacific Northwest; Colorado). August 1910 (Box 27, Folder 21)
- Field Notes (Colorado). August-September 1910 (Box 27, Folder 22)
- Field Notes; Experiments. September-November 1910 (Box 27, Folder 23)
- Experiments. November-December 1910 (Box 27, Folder 24)
- Experiments. November-December 1910 (Box 27, Folder 25)
- Experiments (Roots in Tubs). 1910-1911 (Box 27, Folder 26)
- Experiments. 1910-1911 (Box 27, Folder 27)
- A.F. Kidder (Notes By). 1910 (Box 27, Folder 28)
- Photos. 1911 (Box 27, Folder 29)
- Miscellaneous Notes. 1911 (Box 27, Folder 30)
- Miscellaneous Notes (Colorado). June-July 1911 (Box 27, Folder 31)
- Field Notes (Wyoming; Utah; Idaho; Oregon; California). July-August 1911 (Box 27, Folder 32)
- Field Notes (California; Nevada; Utah). August 1911 (Box 27, Folder 33)
- Field Notes (Colorado). September 1911 (Box 27, Folder 34)
- Rate of Drying. 1911 (Box 27, Folder 35)
- Photos. 1912 (Box 28, Folder 36)
- Plants (Akron, Colorado). 1912 (Box 28, Folder 37)
- Field Notes (Utah). May-June 1912 (Box 28, Folder 38)
- Experiments. July 1912 (Box 28, Folder 39)
- Field Notes (Western Pacific; Colorado). August-September 1912 (Box 28, Folder 40)
- Photos. 1913 (Box 28, Folder 41)
- Photos. 1913 (Box 28, Folder 42)
- Field Notes (Washington, DC to Florida). March-May 1913 (Box 28, Folder 43)
- Dominance of a Species. April 1913 (Box 28, Folder 44)
- Field Notes (Colorado). July-August 1913 (Box 28, Folder 45)
- Field Notes (Colorado; Utah). August 1913 (Box 28, 45a)
- Field Notes (Nevada). September 1913 (Box 28, Folder 46)
- Field Notes (Nevada). September 1913 (Box 28, Folder 47)
- Field Notes (Utah; Nebraska; Washington). September 1913-February 1916 (Box 28, Folder 48)
- Field Notes (Utah). September 1913 (Box 28, Folder 48a)
- Field Notes (Colorado). July-September 1913 (Box 28, Folder 49)
- Field Notes (Washington, DC to Florida). January 1914 (Box 28, Folder 50)
- Growth of Plants Under Water. 1913-1914 (Box 28, Folder 51)
- Photos. 1914 (Box 28, Folder 52)
- Field Notes (Florida). January 1914 (Box 28, Folder 53)
- Field Notes (Colorado; Texas; Oklahoma). April-May 1914 (Box 28, Folder 54)
- Field Notes (Colorado). May-July 1914 (Box 28, Folder 55)
- Field Notes (Colorado; South Dakota). June-August 1914 (Box 28, Folder 56)
- Plants (Colorado). July 1914 (Box 28, Folder 57)
- Plants (Colorado). July 1914 (Box 28, Folder 58)
- Field Notes (Colorado). July-September 1914 (Box 28, Folder 59)
- Chlorophyll. 1914-1916 (Box 28, Folder 60)
- Wilting Plants (Colorado). August 1914 (Box 28, Folder 61)
- Field Notes (Utah). September 1914 (Box 28, Folder 62)
- Field Notes (Utah). September 1914 (Box 28, Folder 62a)
- Experiments (Akron, Colorado). 1914 (Box 28, Folder 63)
- Photos, A-Z. 1915 (Box 28, Folder 64)
- Photos, AA-ZZ. 1915 (Box 28, Folder 65)
- Early Trip West to Denver & Return to Chicago. March-September 1915 (Box 28, Folder 66)
- Field Notes (Arizona, Colorado; Wyoming; Utah; Nevada; California; Oregon). March-June 1915 (Box 28, Folder 67)
- Field Notes (Colorado). June 1915 (Box 28, Folder 68)
- Leaf Temperatures. 1915 (Box 28, Folder 69)
- Leaf Temperatures. 1915 (Box 28, Folder 70)
- Field Notes (Colorado). August 1915 (Box 28, Folder 71)
- Field Notes (Colorado). August 1915 (Box 28, Folder 72)
- Field Notes (Colorado). 1915 (Box 29, Folder 73)
- Field Notes (Colorado). September 1915 (Box 29, Folder 74)
- Field Notes (Utah). 1915 (Box 29, Folder 74a)
- Field Notes (Utah). September 1915 (Box 29, Folder 75)
- Field Notes (Utah; Nevada; California). September 1915 (Box 29, Folder 76)
- Photos. 1916 (Box 29, Folder 77)
- Field Notes (Colorado; Nebraska). June-July 1916 (Box 29, Folder 78)
- Field Notes (Colorado; Texas; New Mexico). June 1916 (Box 29, Folder 79)
- Field Notes (New Mexico). June 1916 (Box 29, Folder 80)
- Ant Hills (Akron, Colorado). July 1916 (Box 29, Folder 81)
- Field Notes (Wyoming; Montana; Washington). August-September 1916 (Box 29, Folder 82)
- Field Notes (Wyoming; Montana; Washington.) August-September 1916 (Box 29, Folder 83)
- Feild Notes (Ontario), Plans for 1917.. September 1916 (Box 29, Folder 84)
- Field Notes (Nevada; California). September 1916 (Box 29, Folder 85)
- Field Notes (Nevada; New Mexico). September-October 1916 (Box 29, Folder 86)
- Field Notes ( New Mexico; Texas). October 1916 (Box 29, Folder 87)
- Photos. 1917 (Box 29, Folder 88)
- Soil Temperatures (Akron, Colorado). 1917 (Box 29, Folder 89)
- Beginning Growth of Temperature (Akron, Colorado). 1917 (Box 29, Folder 90)
- Field Notes (California; Montana; Wyoming; Colorado). April-October 1917 (Box 29, Folder 91)
- Field Notes (Idaho). August-September 1917 (Box 29, Folder 92)
- Field Notes (California; New Mexico). November-December 1917 (Box 29, Folder 93)
- Field Notes (New Mexico). December 1917 (Box 29, Folder 94)
- Photos. 1918 (Box 29, Folder 95)
- Field Notes (Calfornia). January 1918 (Box 29, Folder 96)
- Field Notes (Arizona; Texas). February 1918 (Box 29, Folder 97)
- Field Notes (Arizona; New Mexico; Colorado). May-July 1918 (Box 29, Folder 98)
- Leaf Area Det. (Chula Vista, California). 1918 (Box 29, Folder 99)
- Field Notes (Montana to Colorado; Colorado to Washington, DC). August 1918 (Box 29, Folder 100)
- Photos (Africa). 1919 (Box 29, Folder 101)
- Field Notes, Itinerary, Expenses (Africa). 1919 (Box 29, Folder 102)
- Miscellaneous Notes (Africa). 1919 (Box 29, Folder 103)
- Cape Town Notes (Africa). 1919 (Box 29, Folder 104)
- Field Notes (Africa). 1919 (Box 29, Folder 105)
- Miscellaneous Notes (Africa). 1919 (Box 29, Folder 106)
- African Plants, #1-1160. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 107)
- African Plants, #1161-1403. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 108)
- Notebook Describing the Above-Listed Plants. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 109)
- Notebook Describing the Above-Listed Plants. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 110)
- Notebook Describing the Above-Listed Plants. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 111)
- Notebook Describing the Above-Listed Plants. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 112)
- Notebook Describing the Above-Listed Plants. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 113)
- Notebook Describing the Above-Listed Plants. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 114)
- Notebook Describing the Above-Listed Plants. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 115)
- Notebook Describing the Above-Listed Plants. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 116)
- Notebook Describing the Above-Listed Plants. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 117)
- Notebook Describing the Above-Listed Plants. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 118)
- Notebook Describing the Above-Listed Plants. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 119)
- Notebook Describing the Above-Listed Plants. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 120)
- Notebook Describing the Above-Listed Plants. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 121)
- Notebook Describing the Above-Listed Plants. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 122)
- Notebook Describing the Above-Listed Plants. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 123)
- Notebook Describing the Above-Listed Plants. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 124)
- Notebook Describing the Above-Listed Plants. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 125)
- Miscellaneous Notes (Africa). May 1920 (Box 30, Folder 126)
- Relation of Root Penetration to Soil Moisture Control. September 1920 (Box 30, Folder 127)
- Diary (Africa). 1920 (Box 30, Folder 128)
- California Trip with Marbut. 1920 (Box 30, Folder 129)
- Diary. 1921 (Box 30, Folder 130)
- Leaf Temperatures (Wareham, Mass.) June-July 1922 (Box 31, Folder 131)
- Field Notes (Cape Cod; Utah; Nevada; Californai; Texas). July-September 1922 (Box 31, Folder 132)
- Field Notes (Texas to Nebraska; Colorado). Leaf Temperatures (Chula Vista, California). September-October 1922 (Box 31, Folder 133)
- Field Notes (Switzerland). July-August 1923 (Box 31, Folder 134)
- Field Notes, Diary, etc. (Africa). January-February 1924 (Box 31, Folder 135)
- Field Notes, Diary, etc. (Africa). February 1924 (Box 31, Folder 136)
- Field Notes, Diary, etc. (Africa). March 1924 (Box 31, Folder 137)
- Field Notes, Diary, etc. (Africa) April-May 1924 (Box 31, Folder 138)
- Field Notes, Diary, etc. (Africa). June-July 1924 (Box 31, Folder 139)
- Miscellaneous Notes on Africa. 1924 (Box 31, Folder 140)
- Films of African Trip (Notes & Identification). 1924 (Box 31, Folder 141)
- Films of African Trip (Notes & Identification). 1924 (Box 31, Folder 142)
- Talks (Mostly on African Trip). 1924-1929 (Box 31, Folder 143)
- Field Notes (North Dakota; Montana). September 1924 (Box 31, Folder 144)
- International Congress of Plant Sciences, Ithaca, NY (Notes, etc.). August 16-23, 1926 (Box 31, Folder 145)
- Survey of Northern Great Plains. June-August 1927 (Box 31, Folder 146)
- Personal Observations. Ecology Field Course, University of Arizona, Held in Northern Arizona. Field Notes (Mexico Trip). 1928-1932 (Box 31, Folder 147)
- Diary and Field Notes U.S.S.R.) 1930 (Box 31, Folder 148)
- Field Notes on Sage Quadrant (Arizona). Notes as President of the University of Arizona. 1926-1931 (Box 31, Folder 149)
- Field Notes (Various Trips, Arizona and Sonora). 1932-1934 (Box 31, Folder 150)
- Diary "Carl Schurz Tour" -Germany. July-August 1934 (Box 31, Folder 151)
- Diary and Notes. 1934 (Box 31, Folder 152)
- Diary (Mostly Blank; Few Notes of Meetings). 1936 (Box 32, Folder 153)
- Field Notes (Salt Lake Conference on Soil Conservation Program). March 1936 (Box 32, Folder 154)
- Photos. 1936 (Box 32, Folder 155)
- Field Notes (New Mexico; Arizona). June 1936 (Box 32, Folder 156)
- Field Notes (Springerville, Arizona). June 1936 (Box 32, Folder 157)
- Field Notes (California). July 1936 (Box 32, Folder 158)
- Field Notes (California; Oregon). July 1936 (Box 32, Folder 159)
- Field Notes (Oregon; Washington; Idaho). Notes on 16th Annual Convention, Western States Fish and Game Commissioners, San Francisco. July-August 1936 (Box 32, Folder 160)
- Field Notes (Montana; Utah). August 1936 (Box 32, Folder 161)
- Field Notes (Arizona; Utah; Idaho; Colorado). August 1936 (Box 32, Folder 162)
- Field Notes; Diary (Michigan; Montana; Various Meetings). August-September 1936 (Box 32, Folder 163)
- Field Notes (Minnesota; Wisconsin; Michigan). September 1936 (Box 32, Folder 164)
- Field Notes (North Carolina; Missouri; Oregon; Various Meetings). October-November 1936 (Box 32, Folder 165)
- Notes on Various Meetings. November-December 1936-February 1937 (Box 32, Folder 166)
- Photos turned in to photographic collection, Forest Service. 1937 (Box 32, Folder 167)
- Field Notes (Eastern Colorado). April-May 1937 (Box 32, Folder 168)
- Field Notes (Colorado; Montana). May-June 1937 (Box 32, Folder 169)
- Field Notes (Montana; California). June-August 1937 (Box 32, Folder 170)
- Field Notes (Colorado; Arizona; Montana). August-September 1937 (Box 32, Folder 171)
- Field Notes (Arizona; Virginia). September 1937 & May 1938 (Box 32, Folder 172)
- Field Notes (Atlanta, GA; Syracuse, NY). November-December 1937 (Box 32, Folder 173)
- Field Notes (Various Kinds). March-April 1938 (Box 32, Folder 174)
- Field Notes (Alaska). June 1938 (Box 32, Folder 175)
- Field Notes (Alaska). June-July 1938 (Box 32, Folder 176)
- Field Notes (Alaska). July 1938 (Box 32, Folder 177)
- Field Notes (Alaska). August 1938 (Box 32, Folder 178)
- Field Notes (Arizona; New Mexico; Minnesota). August-September 1938 (Box 32, Folder 179)
- Notes on San Francisco Conference. February 1939 (Box 32, Folder 180)
- Field Notes (Virginia; West Virginia). May 1939 (Box 32, Folder 181)
- Field Notes (California) and Notes on Various Meetings. June-July 1939 (Box 32, Folder 182)
- Field Notes: "Great Plains" (Montana to Flagstaff, Arizona). August 1939 (Box 32, Folder 183)
- Field Notes (Kaibab, Arizona). August 1939 (Box 32, Folder 184)
- Field Notes (Arizona). Audubon Society Meeting, NY. October 1939; September 1934 (Box 32, Folder 185)
- Field Notes (Colorado; Utah; Wyoming; California; Oregon; Montana). January-March 1940 (Box 32, Folder 186)
- Field Notes (Eastern Colorado). June 1940 (Box 32, Folder 187)
- Field Notes (Arizona; Colorado; Wyoming) and Notes on Vaious Meetings. July-August 1940 (Box 32, Folder 188)
- Field Notes (New England). February 1941 (Box 33, Folder 189)
- Field Notes (California; Nevada; Washington; Oregon; Idaho). April-May 1941 (Box 33, Folder 190)
- Field Notes (Utah; Colorado) and Notes of Various Meetings. June-September 1941 (Box 33, Folder 191)
- Notes of Meeting of Western Association of Fish & Game Commissioners, Jackson Hole, Wyoming; and a Conference on Lifestock in Denver. September 1942 (Box 33, Folder 192)
- Field Notes (Wyoming; Montana; Pacific Northwest) and Notes on Meetings. Notes on Reading about Early Western Travels. June-August 1943 (Box 33, Folder 193)
- Mostly Notes on Reading about Game in the National Forests (Will Barnes). 1943 (Box 33, Folder 194)
- Various Notes on Wildlife, and Reading about Early Western Travels. 1944 (Box 33, Folder 195)
- Field Notes (Colorado; California). 1945-1946 & 1948 (Box 33, Folder 196)
- Field Notes (Colorado; Saguaro National Park, Arizona). Notes on Shantz Week, Stillwater, OK; Notes on Reading, Field Notes (Arizona). 1948-1950 (Box 33, Folder 197)
- Field Notes (Colorado). June-August 1949 (Box 33, Folder 198)
- Field Notes (Colorado). August 1949 (Box 33, Folder 199)
- Home Notes on 1949 and Previous Field Notes. 1949 (Box 33, Folder 200)